### JONATHAN HONDA

San Ramon, CA 94583

Phone: (619) 609-3407 | E-mail: hondahelix120@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-honda-778430153 GitHub: https://github.com/hondahelix Portfolio: https://hondahelix.github.io/react-portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Criminology as well as 4+ years of experience with the Army's customs and courtesies through ROTC and holds an Active secret clearance from the Defense Industrial Security Clearance Office (DISCO). Effective at combining resilience with problem solving to create dynamic web applications.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, React, JSX, JSON, ES6

Applications: Web API, Rest API, Postman, AJAX, node.js, jQuery, Express.js, passport, bcrypt, React hooks, Bootstrap,

Sequelize ORM, MySQL, Mongoose ORM, Mongodb, cloudinary Materialize, Heroku, Git, GitHub

#### **PROJECTS**

# Travel Pins | GitHub: https://github.com/anusontarangkul/travel-pins | Deployed Project: https://travel-pins.herokuapp.com

- Co-developed a travel social media application
- Formulated the backend server, database, Rest API, and worked on the frontend javascript
- Contributed over 80% of the additions made to the repository
- Applied tools / languages used: JavaScript, SQL, CSS, HTML, JSX, JSON, ES6, node.js, bcryptjs, cloudinary, Express, express-session, if-env, mysql2, passport, passport-local, sequelize, mapbox-gl, re-carousel, react, react-dom, react-icons, react-router-dom, react-scripts, react-spring, react-swipeable, react-transition-group, web-vitals

### Employment Buddy|GitHub: https://github.com/hondahelix/employment-buddy|Deployed Project: https://employmentbuddy.herokuapp.com

- Co-developed an application to assist users in staying organized during the job hunting process
- Primarily managed frontend JavaScript as well as API calls
- Tools / languages used: Javascript, CSS, HTML, SQL, bcrypt.js, dragula.js, Express, jQuery, mySQL, passport, sequelize, Bulma, Undraw, Font Awesome

## Google Book Search | GitHub: https://github.com/hondahelix/google-book-search | Deployed Project: https://salty-chamber-90587.herokuapp.com

- Co-developed MERN application that utilizes the Google Books API search for and adds a book to a reading list
- Designed the front-end code to display relevant information to the user and the routes to save the data
- Applied tools / languages used: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JSX, React, Axios, Express, Mongoose, Mongodb, React-Router-Dom

#### EXPERIENCE

### **Network Officer/Division Signal Company**

2020 – Present Los Alamitos, CA

Responsible for maintaining the Army's voice, data, and information systems as well as the development and readiness of a platoon

### Cadet Troop Leader Training/510th Clearance Company, 20th Engineering Battalion

2019 –2019 Fort Hood, TX

Acted as platoon leader for a 32-soldier route clearance platoon with the mission to rapidly deploy to a combat theater and execute explosive hazard detection. Responsible for planning, resourcing, coordinating, fitness, professional development, discipline, and combat readiness of the platoon for three weeks.

### EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley - Full-Stack Web Development

September 2020 - December 2020

University of California, Irvine - BA Criminology, Law, and Society

September 2016 - September 2020